AAR has launched a new plan called Elevate with very exciting and unique features and options.
It is a very unique plan.
It has such features which are
industry first. Till date, we have
not seen such features in any plan.
Friends, today we will decode this plan in detail.
We will understand all its features and benefits in detail. What are its pros,
what are its cons, what are its premiums.
We will analyze them in detail.
Along with this, we get 22 add-ons with this plan.
We will discuss all the add-ons
and will also try to know
which add-on we should take with our policy.
And finally, we will also see
whether this plan is really so amazing,
so unique, should we take this plan
or not. Hello
friends, I am Ashutosh, your personal
finance coach. Let's start the video. The
four most unique features of this plan are
Infine.
This means that once in a policy
lifetime, you can claim any amount,
even if your policy is 10 lakhs.  Whether the
claim amount is Rs 20 lakh, Rs 80 lakh, Rs
90 lakh or Rs 1 crore,
you can make a claim for any amount.
Next is the Infighting Bonus. So, in this plan,
we get Infighting Bonus. There are
many plans in which we get 2x coverage,
some 3x, some 4x, some 5x. There are some
plans which give us 10x coverage. So,
this plan has ended this 5x, 10x cycle.
In this plan, the Infighting
Bonus gets added to our basic sum
and there is no limit on it. It will be
unlimited times. It will become 10x in 10 years,
20x in 20 years, 30x in 30 years
and if it reaches 40 years, it will become 40x. This
means that there is no need to fear inflation,
nor do you need to take any super top-up plan.
This plan has
eliminated the tension of both inflation and super top-up.
Next is Infighting Rs
1 Crore 2  3 crore with maximum
coverage up to 56 CR. But if you
feel that considering future inflation
or 56 CR will not be sufficient, then the
company has given you the option of unlimited sum insured
in which there will be
no maximum limit on sum insured, be it 10
CR, 15 CR, 25 CR or anything.
Unlimited means unlimited.
Apart from this, it provides the benefit of unlimited time reset.
Talking about basic eligibility, the minimum entry age is 18 years
and there is no maximum entry age, it is
written as 125 years. This means that
maximum you can enter any age group,
even if you are a senior citizen. There
is no capping of 65, 75. Sum insured option 5,
7.5, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20, 25, 50, 1 CR, 3 CR
and unlimited sum insured so 3 CR  Above this,
you get an unlimited sum insured option, which
means there is no limit on the sum insured. For this
option, you get options of 1 year, 2 years, 3
years, and family floater for two
adults and three children.
Another good option of this plan is
that dependent children
can stay in this plan till the age of up to 30 years.
In most plans, we have to shift them to a new plan after 25-26 years.
Let's
discuss some basic features of this plan.
First inpatient hospitalization: So,
any hospitalization above 24 hours
up to the sum insured will be covered. There is
no capping on room rent, but there is a
capping on the room category. The maximum
available will be only a single private AC room. So,
whether your sum insured is Rs 10 lakh, Rs 15 lakh, Rs 50
lakh, Rs 2 crore or unlimited sum
insured, but the inbuilt room category is
single private AC room, which I
think is the best option for this plan.  One of the most
negative points of the plan is that when you are offering such a higher sum shot,
unlimited sum shot, then
why have you put a capping on the room category?
Friends, this capping
is very important because if you take a room
of a category higher than a single private AC room, then in such a situation,
you
not only have to pay the difference in room rent,
but the cost of your overall treatment
increases proportionately. In such a situation,
if you are taking a room higher than a single private AC room, then
you have to keep in mind that it is
necessary to modify the room category with this plan because if you will
rely only on a single private AC room
and you ever go to a hospital for treatment and
that category is not available there, only the
room of the higher category is available. In such a situation,
even if you have a sum shot of two crores, there is going to be a
good deduction from your hospital bill. So, along
with the base plan, you will get at least room category,
modified care treatment, day
treatment, such treatments in which
24 hours  Hospitalization of more than an hour is not
charged, rather due to technological advancement,
that treatment is done in a procedure of a few hours only,
such as cataract
surgery and hernia etc. There are many
surgeries which are done in procedures of a few hours,
so such treatments will also be
covered up to the sum. Organ donor
expenses, so inpatient treatment till harvesting of the donor will be
covered
in your policy. Pre and post hospitalization,
pre hospitalization up to 90 days and
post hospitalization up to 180 days
are covered in this plan. Domicile hospitalization,
so if in any emergency condition we
cannot take the patient to the hospital
or if there is no bed available in any nearby hospital
and we have
taken hospitalization at home, then this domicile
hospitalization is also covered up to the sum.
Alternative treatment or AYUSH treatment,
Ayurvedic, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy,
if we take any alternative treatment related to these, then
that too will be covered up to the sum.
Reimbursement and cashless both will be
available. Next is  Domestic Road
Ambulance:
Actual charges will be available on the age for domestic road ambulance. There is
no capping on it.
Charges up to sum sum will be available for road ambulance.
Next is reset benefit.
Like we also know it as restore refill recharge
statement. When
our basic sum sum is consumed and
any other hospitalization happens in the same policy year, then
for that the
insurance company refills our basic cover again.
This is reset
benefit. So in this plan, 100% reset
benefit is available to us and it
is available unlimited times. So, if the basic sum sum is
consumed and multiple
hospitalizations are happening in a year, then at
such a time, this restore of unlimited times can be
beneficial.
Also, all the diseases are covered in it, related
and unrelated. There is no
capping or any cooling period for any disease.
Next is surrogacy and other side. So,
inpatient treatment related to surrogacy and other side.
Up to 5 lakhs will be covered. Next benefit
is guaranteed cumulative bonus. So in this plan,
we get an inbuilt cumulative bonus of 20%,
maximum up to 100% and it is
respectful of the claim.
You get this guaranteed bonus whether there is a claim or not. Next
benefit is bariatric surgery. So, all obesity-
related surgical treatments should be
covered up to some. A
waiting period of two years will be applicable for that.
Next is discount on service.
So, if you download the company's Il Tech Care app and
register your policy on it, then you
get some discount on various services. Next is
wellness program. So, if you adopt a healthy
lifestyle, go to the gym, do
yoga, then the company
incentivizes you. In this plan, if you
fulfill the required criteria of the company, then you can avail a discount of up to 30%
in your renewal premium.
Next is the health
assistant. So, for your health and health-
related queries, you will get a health assistant.
Assistance Next is the modern
treatment, so there
is no capping related to modern treatment, up to some extent all
modern treatments will be covered. Let's
discuss the advances of this plan. There are 22
advances in this plan. In
order to make the base plan cheaper, nothing has been kept inbuilt in this plan,
everything has been made an add-on. Now
you keep choosing and
keep increasing your premium. The first important add-on
is Power Booster, in which you
get a cumulative bonus of 100% for unlimited times. So the
system of 1x, 5x, 10x has been abolished.
As long as you keep renewing the policy,
you will keep getting a cumulative bonus of 100%. So if you do it
for 10 years, it will become 10x, 20x in 20 years,
30x in 30 years and 40x if you do it for 40 years, it will become 40x.
Meaning, your policy of Rs 10 lakh will become Rs
1 crore in 10 years, Rs 2 crore in 20 years and Rs
3 crore in 30 years. So this is a
very good benefit.  To
counter inflation, you wo
n't need a super top-up if you're
getting such a good sum assured bonus
with your policy. The next important
benefit is InfaCare, which gives you the
option to make a
claim for any amount once in your policy's lifetime.
You might have a policy worth Rs 10 lakh with a
sum assured bonus of Rs 203 lakh, but
you receive a claim of Rs 80 lakh, Rs 90 lakh, or Rs 1
crore. In this InfaCare, you
get the option to make a claim for any
amount. So,
if you have a policy worth Rs 5 lakh or Rs 10 lakh, or a
short-term policy,
you can definitely consider this option.
Even with a power booster, it will take you
10 to 15 years to develop a sum assured of Rs 1.5 crore.
So, in the
meantime, you can provide coverage for at least one claim.
Next, for an unlimited claim amount,  The rider is of
inflation protector, so this rider keeps
increasing the basic sum according to inflation, so whatever is the government's
inflation target at 5, 6, 7,
it will also keep increasing your basic sum,
so if you have power booster with your policy then there is
no need to take this rider and if you are not
taking power booster then there is no need to take this plan also,
so ultimately I don't think
what is going to be the use of inflation protector,
if you already have power
booster then you are already getting 100% cumulative bonus, the
next important
benefit is jump start in which you
get coverage without any waiting period in case of asthma, diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia i.e. high cholesterol and obesity, so if we have any pre-
existing condition then
we have to serve some waiting period for that, the
waiting period in this plan is
of 10 years, but if you want this lifestyle  If
you have certain diseases, you can get cover for
all your diseases without serving any waiting period
with this rider.
Diabetes and hypertension have become very common these days.
India is already being called the diabetes capital. So, having
these
lifestyle diseases at a young age has become very common. So,
if you have any such condition
in these listed conditions, then definitely you can
consider this rider with your policy. The
next important rider is
Claim Protector. So, there are many non-
payable items, consumables,
which are not covered inbuilt in your policy.
PPE kits, syringes, cotton, there are many such
things whose charges are
not covered by health insurance. So, whether
you have a policy of Rs 5 lakh or Rs 50 lakh or Rs 10 lakh,
their charges will not be covered inbuilt. They will be
deducted from your hospital bill amount. These
charges can go up to Rs 5 to 15 or sometimes even Rs 20 of the hospital bill.
So, I would
advise you to include this rider in your policy.
This is a very good rider to take with the policy. The
next add-on is domestic air
ambulance, so you can take this rider with you.
According to me, this
benefit should be inbuilt. Still, if
you feel that you may need it
in an emergency, then you can definitely consider this rider. The
next benefit is
dependent accommodation. So, if any insured
is hospitalized, you get accommodation benefits of Rs.
000 per day for a maximum of up to 10 days for one dependent.
If you feel that
you need to take this cash benefit for your dependent, then you
can definitely consider this rider with you. The next important rider is room
modification. You
get a cap of single private AC room inbuilt with it.
You cannot take a room of a higher category.
But it has been seen many times that many times you
go to big hospitals and this room is
not available, then you have to take a room of a higher category. In
such a situation, when  If you
take a higher category room, the overall
treatment cost
increases proportionately. So, when you
claim the hospital bill, there is a significant deduction
in your policy. So, to avoid this kind of
hassle, you
must take this rider with your policy when you room
modify and downgrade. So, we have to
take the upgrade option. In downgrade, there is a capping of
twin sharing room or
1 per sum should be imposed in your policy. So,
you get some benefit discounts for that,
but I would not suggest this.
Our
optional benefit in room modification is Compassion at
Visit, in which if the insured person
is hospitalized for more than five days, then
immediate family member
gets benefits up to Rs 20,000 for economy class air ticket or railway ticket for travel. But this
benefit is inbuilt in many policy plans.
They have kept it separate from the policy and are
giving it as an add-on.  The
benefit is maternity benefit,
for which
charges up to ₹1 lakh will be available at 10 percent off
and there will be a waiting period of 2 years.
Within this maternity benefit, there is
also the benefit of newborn baby cover and vaccination
benefit.
Twice the maternity sum for newborn baby cover is ₹1 lakh.
Maximum ₹1 lakh will be
available for newborn baby cover
and charges up to ₹10,000 will be available
for vaccination. However, if we
look at the premium, this
is not a maternity plan. Its maternity
premium is quite high. If you want to
take a maternity plan, then you
can look at Health Advantage, in which you have to pay
2 years' premium upfront.
If you are looking for health insurance only for maternity, then
both of these are
not the right plans for maternity. There are
many other good options for that.
I would not recommend this rider at all. The
next benefit with this plan
is Nursing at Home. In which if
you require nursing after hospitalization,
then
[Music]
₹2000000 per year is the next benefit.
So, if the hospitalization is more than 10 days, then the
insurance company makes a one-time cash payment of ₹20,000.
This benefit should also be inbuilt.
They have also given this as a rider. The
next benefit is health checkup, for which
% off sum shot charges up to maximum ₹5,000 will be
available, that too on a cashless
basis. There is no reimbursement and on
top of that, they have also given health checkup as a done. At least,
health checkup should be inbuilt
in the policy. The next benefit is done.
If you want OPD cover on a cashless basis with your policy,
then you
can take the Be Fit rider, in which apart from OPD, you
also get the benefits of pharmacy, physiotherapy and diagnostics.
Next  Teleconsultation: So if you
want teleconsultation with your policy,
then you can take this rider in which you
get the benefit of unlimited time teleconsultation from health care
professionals. But I think this rider should also be
inbuilt. At least,
you should have provided inbuilt teleconsultation. The next
optional benefit is the option to reduce
maternity benefit. The inbuilt
time limit for maternity is two years. If you want, you
can also make it one year. But as I already
told you, the
cost of this maternity rider is quite high. If you
reduce that waiting period, then its cost will become
even higher. In such a situation, this is
not advisable. The next optional benefit
is voluntary payment, in which you
get the option of voluntary payment up to 10 percent, 20 percent, 30 percent, 40 percent and 50 percent. If you
take this payment, then you
get a huge discount on the premium. So
if you feel that your premium is
becoming unaffordable, then you  You
can select this voluntary payment.
Mostly, for senior citizens of higher age,
we often have to opt for co-payment
because without co-payment the
premium becomes very high. The
next optional benefit is Network
Advantage. Every hospital has
a list of preferred networks. Similarly,
if you get treatment in ICICI's preferred network
hospitals and
take this rider, you
get a discount of 10% on your premium. However,
if you go for treatment in any hospital other than the preferred network,
you will have to
pay 20%. So I would
advise you to pay a slightly higher premium and not be fooled by
discounts. Stay
away from these PPN listed riders. The
next optional benefit is Personal
Accident. If your policy
offers a lump sum benefit in case of accidental death or disability, then you
can take this rider. The next optional
benefit is Critical Illness, which is a 20%
critical illness.  It covers illnesses and gives
you a lump sum benefit payout upon detection of these illnesses.
So if you
feel that you need to take a cover for a critical illness, then
you can definitely consider it.
We also get some discounts in this plan. The
first is the wellness discount,
for which we can get a discount of up to 30%. The
next discount in the renewal premium is the credit score
discount. If your credit score is good and
healthy, then you
can get a discount of up to 15%. For this, make
sure that your correct number is updated
in your KYC document. Apart from this, we get a long
tenure discount on multi-year policies, in
which on taking a two-year policy, we get a discount of
10% on the second year premium
and on taking a three-year policy,
we get a discount of up to 15% on the third year premium.
Talking about waiting periods, the
initial waiting period is 30 days. The pre-
assisting disease waiting period is 36 months
and the specific waiting period is 24 months.  There is
a specific
waiting period for growing illnesses, which is
common industry-wise. Treatments like cataract, hernia, knee
replacement, etc. have a
waiting
period of 2 years. The critical illness waiting
period is 90 days, but there is no
survival period for critical illnesses. If you have
taken a critical illness rider,
you will receive its benefits without any survival period. There is a
24-month waiting period for bariatric surgery, and a
90-day waiting period is applicable for undisclosed hypertension, diabetes, and cardiac conditions. The
inbuilt waiting period for maternity is 24 months. This
plan offers a zone-wise premium,
which is divided into four zones:
Zones A, B, C, and D. There is no zone-wise copayment.
You may reside in any zone, have paid premiums for any zone,
and you can get treatment
in any other zone without paying any copayment.
But this does
not mean that you can get treatment in any other zone without paying any copayment.  If you live in Zone 1
and your hometown is in Zone 3 or Zone 4,
you're paying the premium there
and are going for treatment in Zone 1. In
such a situation, you may face a problem.
You have to pay the premium for the place where you live.
If there is
any change in your permanent address, you have to
intimate this to the insurance company and
update your address and pay the
premium according to your address.
Talking about the premium, for the premium,
I have taken the example of a 30-year-old couple
in Daily NCR Zone A, for which
I have insured Rs 10 lakh, which is a quite
fair value.
However, if we add a maternity rider to it, the
premium goes up to Rs 70,000,
which is quite high in my opinion.
And if you increase the maternity waiting period from
two years to one year, then the
premium becomes more than Rs 1 lakh.
That's why I said that this is
not a maternity plan; its maternity
premium is quite high, friends.  If
you have any doubt regarding this plan,
you can ask me by commenting below.
Friends, if you want to take your health insurance
with me or
want to discuss health insurance with me, then call me on the number given below.